last episode i started the upside down
mansion and i want to continue that this
episode but i've been sitting on this
ledge trying to work my way up into
building this a bit more and i realized
it's really really lonely here like
there's no one
there's nothing just me and the piglens
and a whole lot of lava so what we're
going to do today is send over some
invitations to our fellow hermits to see
if anyone else wants to join now i would
love to keep this whole thing the theme
upside down they could make an upside
down base over here over here or
whatever and we can all come up with
some really cool ways of entertaining
each other in this region make some
farms and generally just build up this
area in the nether and make our own
little
little fun community here
tame the nether that's the goal so i'm
going to need to go back all the way
back to the shopping district i need to
turn this into an ice and boat system
whoa
when i zoom in this this makes it seem
so weird hold on i've got an even better
idea oh my goodness it looks like we're
falling down a tunnel it straight up
looks like oh my goodness
this is so weird
it feels like we're falling
rather than going sideways oh i'm not
sure i like this
now to get these invites over to people
first we need to decide who are we going
to invite and second all i need lots of
my head i need green faces you'll see
why in a minute
hopefully
there's uh there's none here i don't
think i have any green heads
while we're here we might as well uh
take in all the diamonds casual 46
diamonds not too shabby look at this
look how many diamonds the barge is
making over time it's getting it's
getting quite a lot there's a fair
amount of profit there but what i really
need is my face there is one way to get
your face and
it requires
it requires the help of someone else
and the only other person online is
mumbo who i was actually going to invite
anyway so let's find mumbo and ask a
quick favor of him i need a mumbo
detection service he's not in his base
but i'm just going to put a block of
netherrack there to add to the bird's
still there wool still there right where
is he oh he's there he's got a bamboo
suit on hi mumbo i just need you
one sec
i need a favor kill me
he didn't even hesitate he didn't even
ask a sing he didn't even ask a single
question he just did he just did it and
again he didn't even not even for a
second he's not like he didn't ask why
he didn't he didn't ask anything again
zero hesitation he didn't even stutter
again
more
[Music]
he must be so confused more please
i am once again asking for your sword
services
my hero my job here is done
that's interesting he did he didn't even
question for one second what if i was
joking mumbo just said he has three
heads but i just i just came back to get
the three heads from mumbo and i went
under his base and there's a box here
that says don't open i'm sorry how can i
not open this box do i open the box
there was uh nothing in it
no
cursed mumbo no mumbo must be so
confused okay now that we've got the
green heads for the invitations all we
need now are these the grindstones and
here's how we here's how we do it we
make a green invitation delivery system
so i'll put the invitation in the
shulker box like this and then this is
the body the legs the arms and then we
put boom
this
[Laughter]
this is how we deliver
the invitation to the upside down oh no
i think i'm in love
grab
need to grab some books
i don't have to pay myself
and write out the same message
to all the people we want to invite
grumble grumble still grumble's still
okay he's still happy in there i think
the first place we're gonna go is to
b-dubs his base but the problem is
i can never find bdubs base i always
just basically fly around the entire
island or it's not even an island is it
ah that's corrales
which means i've gone the wrong way i
very rarely venture
outside of the jungle too much so this
is uh it's it's been a while since i've
been around here
there's there's tango's toon towers and
there's a target that i have to
definitely fly into the bullseye
wow look at this false's base looking
phenomenal oh my goodness i found it
i found the mansion from season six and
then bdubs his base is just over the
hill my goodness this place is amazing
he built an entire mountain for a
backdrop this is why we need him this is
why we need b-dubs in the upside down
now i think this one is his main house
so just in here i think we can pop our
delivery green delivery number one
dear bdubs you are cordly invited to
join the upside down a new hip and
happening place in the nether literally
everyone wants to be there we don't want
to seem lonely chords are here follow
the yellow brick road come and build
something anything you like would be
cool if it was upside down though green
done
an invitation now is there a way to copy
these unless you just do this oh there
we go oh no oh no they're all addressed
to be dubs
[Laughter]
whoops b-dubs is getting probably gonna
end up with more than one invitation
imagine coming into your house and
seeing
that why hello there right we've got
more people to invite and now i need to
figure out how to get out here it turns
out bdubs doesn't even have a portal or
if he does i can't find it so we're
going to start out with just a few
invitations to begin with and then if
it's successful we don't want to be
overcrowded straight away so we'll
invite just a couple people and see how
it goes we've got to invite mumbo but i
think it's way better in fact let's put
it somewhere that he's definitely not
going to find it straight away
but after a while let's put it on top of
this lovely parrot
delivery green number two number two
dear number you are cordially invited to
join the upside down yada yada literally
all of humanity want to live there the
coordinates come over build something it
would be cool if the builds are upside
down but they don't have to be done
what does this look like from a distance
oh you just see a couple of grind
you just see a couple of grindstones
and then as you get closer boom green
face i'm sure he'll notice that
although mumbo is incredible oh oh
no
[Music]
broken broken wings looks like we're
walking from here i've never really
understood why the wings don't look
broken once they've actually broken
they look fine actually we've fallen
into just the right place
scar is going to be our next invitation
delivery number three complete
that's three people now i think that
might be enough really for this
that's three invitations that might be
enough for the time being and maybe
we'll do a couple more next episode it
may not even be likely that anybody
takes up my offer now the invites are
out we just need to make the yellow
brick road
hi there now that the invites are done
we need to get back to the upside down
because i don't want people to get there
and be like oh there's not a lot here
we've got to really try and finish that
mansion
before people start accepting the
invitations they may be put off by the
fact that there's just a long tunnel i
still can't get over the fact that this
looks like i'm falling and not flying or
is flying just falling in style well it
took us pretty much all day to get those
invitations out and ready so we might as
well spend the rest of our time
trying to get more done on the upside
down mansion so without further ado
let's get on
get some more done
and probably leave the back open forever
i think this is just becoming a thing
for season seven just forget the back
leave it up and
just leave it alright let's
go
[Music]
[Applause]
so
[Music]
so close yet so far
it is difficult to see what's going on
in those time lapses because of the fog
i mean the nether is completely
different i actually
genuinely think it's not very playable
with the fog on just to remind you what
this mansion will look like with the fog
on you can't see it at all there's
literally nothing
i'm standing in exactly the same place
and you can't even see it so i think if
there's anyone at mojang watching please
push the fog back you can't see anything
unless you turn it off look at this like
it's literally like being unblindfolded
so here we are we've got half a mansion
we've got the middle of the mansion
there is one more piece of the puzzle
and on this part guess what i actually
did build the back
no
gaps here i haven't detailed any of it
apart from there because it's again
unlikely people are gonna go here but i
do plan on actually completing the back
of this one
now this actually ended up costing me a
huge amount of resources i've run out of
pretty much everything so the final
third of the upside down mansion is
probably going to have to wait i would
have done it all in one go although that
did take like 12 hours building upside
down is a nightmare but also
yeah really time intensive this was but
either way i think this looks really
cool it is exactly the same mansion but
for some reason it feels like a
completely different build upside down
my next goal will be to try and mob
proof it probably with carpets to stop
this happening but i feel confident
enough that people could move into this
area and think wow this is a place that
i would like to stay but something
really unfortunate happened
during the construction of this thing
somehow
and honestly i don't know how
but i lost my netherite boots
i lost i've just replaced them with some
gold boots but look how sad is that
netherite is so expensive and i don't
have any spare so for the rest of this
episode i'm going to become the
netherright king i am never going to let
this happen again netherright is so good
but it's also so expensive
so i'm thinking if this happened to me
it probably will happen to someone else
in the future and i can stock the barge
with some very very high value items so
at the moment we've only got 30
whoa
sorry i was about to say we're going to
become the netherright king
but iskall has got 412
pieces of netherrite or ancient debris
we may just be the netherright prince
for this i'm not sure we can beat 412.
we'll see it's unlikely but we're going
to try the minimum that we're going to
do is get back our boots i think we
should check if this guy's had the same
idea as me because i want to sell
netherrite stuff
in here in the barge
gotta up my gamer that freaked me out
i've gotta up my game a little bit oh
man we've had some sales
just keep adding them to the pile
look at this
we just need to check if iskal has had
the same idea
ah i think i know where his netherright
has gone
into this
giant pile leave your leaves behind leaf
it here problems leaf it with bernie
take a leaflet
okay so i've just read the book
basically this is a leaf collecting game
and he needs a lot of leaves and then
the winner gets this pile
i don't think that i'm gonna participate
in this just because i've i've gone for
a lot of leaves in the past it's not fun
i i don't really want to be gathering
thousands of blocks of leaves again even
if that is a very tempting offer i've
got other stuff that i need to do so
good luck to everybody who's
participating but i think
i'm gonna focus on improving the barge
getting more stock and generally
becoming the best shop on the shopping
district
it's been a while since we've upgraded
the barge actually i need to think about
what i'm going to do next so in order to
get the netherreich's i'm going to need
to upgrade my boots
i need tnt
i've tried every method of netherrite
farming and by far
the best is with tnt beds is too slow
mining is really too slow
so it's the most expensive way to do it
because obviously
tnt costs a lot but with a gunpowder
farm and a bit of elbow grease
you can make a lot of tnt
so all there is left to do is to find a
desert where we can mine a lot of sand
and get some tnt made so i can get my
boots back unfortunately i have no idea
where one is
we have ourselves one full shulker box
of tnt now this might not look like an
awful lot but this should be more than
enough
to get started so what we're going to do
is find a place
actually i didn't realize that this
huge chunk
of netherrack is actually floating
that's very interesting that does mean
that perhaps long term this could be
removed although it takes hours just to
remove a small segment this could be
removed anyway i think what we'll do
is we'll take this spot here
and make our way
underground
now the best it's most frequently found
at y15 which is right here so if we go
just a little bit lower about y11
and all we're going to do is make a
really really long line and i'll do a
small one just to show you how this is
done we've done this before on the
channel but this is by far
the most effective way of doing it so we
basically every two do another tnt
and it starts a chain reaction we step
back we let it do its thing
like so
and you there we go and it ends up
revealing a long tunnel with very little
effort see if i had just been strip
mining i would have gone straight under
that so what we're gonna do is get into
a big time lapse because we are about to
use
all of this
in one
big
go
which should be
insane absolutely insane so let's start
by making broken netherrack mid go we'll
start by making a long tunnel and
filling it up
[Music]
so
this was pretty successful i actually i
was actually pretty unlucky with this i
got 39 ancient debris which
is quite a lot on the face of it but
there were so many of these tunnels that
were just empty i i
don't know if i've missed some but yeah
i feel like i wasn't as lucky as i could
have been still that is more than enough
to get my boots back and i actually
barely made a dent in the tnt so i used
eight stacks of tnt which
is is quite a lot of tnt but
if we went on averages i would be able
to get
quite quite a lot more ancient debris
when i use that but i'm going to save
that for next episode because i am
desperately running out of time but i
think we'll use the rest of this
in the next episode however i can't seem
to find my way out this is not a joke
and this is not a drill i can't get out
i don't know where the exit is i've made
too many tunnels and another stressful
factor is all my pickaxes are running
relatively low honestly i think the best
option is to just mine upwards from here
and see where we get and hope that we
don't run into lava like that like that
oh my goodness i've totally come out
onto a bastion what a stroke of luck
now has this been found already
now i've learned my lesson if you open a
chest the piglins get very very angry
with you so
you've got to close yourself in when you
open something so they don't know what
you're up to
and we've got ourselves
a big loot chest
let's play it safe
i've got too much ancient debris on me
for me to mess this up
this is a rather disappointing chest
where are all the piglins i can hear
them
um okay i'm not sure what's going on
here but there is a party in a very
small space makes this makes this a lot
easier doesn't look like there's a whole
lot more to be found in this bastion i
might be crazy but i think i'm actually
spawned in a box
this bastion has completely formed
underground
i don't actually know how to get out of
here
it's sealed in on all sides so hopefully
if we just dig up we can get out again
now that is really weird
oh no
i think i think the bastion continues
this is the strangest bastion i've ever
seen freedom okay let's see if we can
find the mansion from here oh my god
it's right there
i mean we went on a bit of an adventure
for all of this ancient debris let's get
out of here so now i just need to smelt
up this ancient debris
and then combine with gold to create
netherright ingots
so we need to head back to the base and
get ourselves some fresh boots we buy
ourselves some boots pop them in an
upgrade
put them in a smoothing table and we got
ourselves
netherright
boots now we put the rest of the ingots
in here because next episode i'm hoping
we can improve this to a lot more
now b-dubs is online
but i can't help but notice he hasn't
responded to my very kind invitation to
the upside down now this just won't fly
if he's not at his base what we're going
to do is try and ramp up the amount of
invitations so that he can't ignore us
so let's head back to b-dubs his base
and really ramp things up
doesn't look like he's here
just doing a quick double check
not building on his insane mountain
here he is his delivery green see the
invite is done
always breathe right there
oh no
bad timing it's right there
okay i think he's left looks like he's i
think he's flown off
i can't see him anymore now
we make the army of delivery greens one
two three i can't help but feel i'm
wasting all of my korean heads for this
gag
and one
one more
done
oh my goodness now i don't have lots of
the same invite so i'm just gonna like
rename this paper
invitation to upside
down come on b-dubs you can't ignore
this
imagine b-dubs coming back
to his base just to find
this monstrosity i think that's enough
antics for now hopefully they will
accept the invitation to the upside down
and we can get started on some real
building over there but i'm afraid that
is all i have time for today thank you
very very much for watching i hope you
enjoyed this episode and i shall see you
in the next one good bye